我们现在来看一些实际问题，其中之一就是可达性。我们的机器人有
Let's look at some practical issues now and one of these is reachability. Our robot has
只有有限的链接。因此，有大量可能的目标位置
only got finite links. So, there are a large number of possible goal locations that the
机器人实际上无法触及。如果该点无法到达那么，
robot is physically just not going to be able to reach. If the point is unreachable then,
它通常会导致我们的反向运动学解决方案出现一些问题。一个数字
it will generally lead to some problem in our inverse kinematics solution. A numerical
算法将无法收敛。对于分析方法，我们可能最终找到
algorithm will fail to converge. For an analytic approach, we may end up finding
我们正在计算负数的平方根，或者我们可能发现我们是
that we're computing the square root of a negative number or we may find that we're
计算幅度大于1的数的反cos符号。
computing the inverse cos sign of a number whose magnitude is greater than 1.
在我们的反向运动学中会出现一些数值问题。另一个问题是奇点
Some numerical problem will crop up in our inverse kinematics. Another problem is a singularity
这与我们看到的万向节锁问题有很多相似之处
and this has got a lot of similarities to the Gimbal lock problem that we looked at
更早。在这里，我们可以看到Prima560的手腕
much earlier. Here, we can see the wrist of a Prima 560
机器人，我们可以看到，在这个特殊的配置中，第4关节的轴是
robot and we can see that in this particular configuration, the axis of the 4th joint is
平行于第6关节的轴。它现在将动画这个机器人，看看是什么
parallel to the axis of the 6th joint. It would be now animate this robot and look what
当我们移动机器人的关节4时发生。整个手腕组件都像这样移动
happens when we move joint 4 of the robot. The whole wrist assembly moves like this and
现在我们要移动机器人的关节6。我们看到它导致完全相同的排序
now we're going to move joint 6 of the robot. We see that it causes exactly the same sort
末端执行器的运动。现在，我们要做的是对抗旋转关节4
of motion of the end effector. Now, what we're going to do is to counter rotate joints 4
因此，如果关节4增加，关节6正在减小，最终结果是关节4
and joint 6 so if joint 4 is increasing, joint 6 is decreasing, net result being that the
结束因素根本不动。所以，就像在GimbalLock案中一样，我们已经输了
end factor does not move at all. So, just as in Gimbal Lock case, we've lost
自由法令。关节4和关节6导致完全相同的运动
the decree of freedom. Joint 4 and joint 6 result in exactly the same motion that the
机器人末端效应器和机器人技术，我们称之为奇点。
robots end effector and in robotics, we refer to this as a singularity.
实际意义上的含义是接头4和接头6的轴线是否对齐
What it means in practical sense is if the axis of joints 4 and joint 6 are aligned like
这就是机器人末端执行器不可能采用某些特定的方向。
this then it's not possible for the robot end effector to adopt some particular orientations.
为了打破这种对齐，摆脱奇点，重要的是
In order to break that alignment, to move out of singularity, it's important that the
第五关节角θ5设定为不等于0的某个值。
5th joint angle theta 5 is set to some value that's not equal to 0.